<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Debtor Mark Content</name>
        <update version="0.0.7">
            <file name="DebtorMark.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Trickderap/CustomDnDContentByTricktheTrickster/refs/heads/main/DebtorMark.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Trick's Ledger of Many Tricks" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_TRICK_SOURCE_HOMEBREW">
        <description>
            <p>A collection of high-stakes archetypes and forbidden probability magic.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TLoMT</set>
            <set name="category">Homebrew</set>
            <set name="url">https://github.com/Trickderap/CustomDnDContentByTricktheTrickster</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Brand of the Dead Man's Wager" type="Item" source="Trick's Ledger of Many Tricks" id="ID_TRICK_ITEM_DEAD_MANS_WAGER">
        <description>
            <p><i>Equip this item in your inventory to activate the mark's feature on your character sheet.</i></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Additional Feature</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
            <set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
        <requirements>
            <requirement name="ID_INTERNAL_ABILITY_WISDOM" value="10" />
        </requirements>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat" id="ID_TRICK_FEAT_DEAD_MANS_WAGER_EFFECT" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Brand of the Dead Man's Wager" type="Feat" source="Trick's Ledger of Many Tricks" id="ID_TRICK_FEAT_DEAD_MANS_WAGER_EFFECT">
        <supports>Feat</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This brand is a <strong>Dead Man's Marker</strong>—a gambling debt signed by a soul that should have departed. It manifests on the back of your hand as <strong>20 iron chain links</strong> surrounding a <strong>sun with 8 rays</strong>. The wager is simple but terrifying: you get your life back, but the Dealer holds an unspecified favor to be called in at their discretion.</p>
            
            <h4>The Metabolic Clock</h4>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Active Phase (Hours 1-8):</strong> You gain <strong>+2 AC</strong>. The sun glows, but one ray extinguishes every hour.</li>
                <li><strong>Burden Phase (Hours 9-20):</strong> The sun is dark. You lose the AC bonus. You cannot Long Rest until the 20th hour passes.</li>
            </ul>

            <h4>Rolling the Bones</h4>
            <p>During the Burden Phase, the odds turn against you. For every hour that passes after the 8th, roll a <strong>d20</strong>. <strong>If you roll a 1</strong>, the Dealer collects interest on the debt.</p>
            <p>If triggered, roll a <strong>d8</strong> on the Corruption Table below:</p>
            
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td>d8</td>
                        <td>Corruption Effect</td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tr>
                    <td>1</td>
                    <td><strong>Singed Nerves:</strong> The chains heat up violently. You take 1d4 fire damage that cannot be reduced.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>2</td>
                    <td><strong>Phantom Weight:</strong> Your movement speed is reduced by 10 feet for 1 hour.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>3</td>
                    <td><strong>Creaking Joints:</strong> Your movements echo with the sound of grinding metal. Disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks for 1 hour.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>4</td>
                    <td><strong>Spectral Whispers:</strong> The debt collectors are watching. Disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks for 1 hour.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>5</td>
                    <td><strong>Lead Arm:</strong> The mark feels impossibly heavy. You have Disadvantage on Strength Ability Checks and Saving Throws for 1 hour.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>6</td>
                    <td><strong>Metabolic Tax:</strong> The mark siphons your vitality. Your <strong>Hit Point Maximum</strong> is reduced by <strong>1d6 + your level</strong> until you finish a Long Rest.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>7</td>
                    <td><strong>Feverish Haze:</strong> The pain clouds your judgment. You have Disadvantage on Intelligence and Charisma Ability Checks for 1 hour.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>8</td>
                    <td><strong>Grace Period:</strong> The burning stops and the chains fade early. <strong>The cooldown ends immediately.</strong> You may begin a Long Rest now if you wish.</td>
                </tr>
            </table>

            <p class="indent"><b>Prerequisite:</b> Wisdom 10 or higher.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>+2 AC for 8 hours. Afterwards, AC bonus is lost. Each hour past 8, roll a d20; on a 1, trigger a Corruption effect. Cannot rest until Hour 20 unless a Grace Period (Roll 8) occurs.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>