<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Feats &amp; Features</name>
        <update version="0.0.6">
            <file name="feat.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Trickderap/CustomDnDContentByTricktheTrickster/refs/heads/main/Mechanics/feat.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Brand of the Dead Man's Wager" type="Feat" source="Trick's Ledger of Many Tricks" id="ID_TRICK_FEAT_DEAD_MANS_WAGER_EFFECT">
        <supports>Feat</supports>
        <description>
            <p><em>"The ink never dries on a contract with the Proprietor. It just burns deeper."</em></p>
            <p>This brand appears on your skin as a searing mark of your debt to the Trickster. It manifests as a burning sun with 8 rays, surrounded by 20 iron chain links that seem to tighten as time passes.</p>
            <h4>The Metabolic Clock</h4>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Active Phase (Hours 1-8):</strong> You gain <strong>+2 AC</strong>. The sun glows, but one ray extinguishes every hour.</li>
                <li><strong>Burden Phase (Hours 9-20):</strong> The sun is dark. You lose the AC bonus. You cannot Long Rest until the 20th hour passes.</li>
            </ul>
            <h4>Rolling the Bones</h4>
            <p>During the Burden Phase, roll a <strong>d20</strong> every hour. <strong>On a 1</strong>, the Dealer collects interest. Roll a d8 on the Corruption Table:</p>
            <table>
                <thead><tr><td>d8</td><td>Effect</td></tr></thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><strong>Singed Nerves:</strong> 1d4 fire damage (unmitigated).</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><strong>Phantom Weight:</strong> Speed reduced by 10 ft for 1 hour.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><strong>Creaking Joints:</strong> Disadvantage on Stealth checks for 1 hour.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><strong>Spectral Whispers:</strong> Disadvantage on Perception checks for 1 hour.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td><strong>Lead Arm:</strong> Disadvantage on Strength Checks/Saves for 1 hour.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td><strong>Metabolic Tax:</strong> Max HP reduced by <strong>1d6 + Level</strong> until Long Rest.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td><strong>Feverish Haze:</strong> Disadvantage on Int/Cha Checks for 1 hour.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td><strong>Grace Period:</strong> Cooldown ends immediately. You may Long Rest.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>+2 AC for 8 hours. Afterwards, AC bonus is lost. Each hour past 8, roll a d20; on a 1, trigger a Corruption effect.</description>
        </sheet>
        
        <requirements>[trick_brand_key:1]</requirements>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Card Shark" type="Feat" source="Trick's Ledger of Many Tricks" id="ID_TRICK_FEAT_CARD_SHARK">
        <requirements>[dex:13]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><em>"It's not gambling if you know you're going to win."</em></p>
            <p>You have mastered the art of throwing cards with deadly precision. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency with playing cards. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</li>
                <li>You can treat ordinary playing cards as simple ranged weapons with the finesse and thrown properties (range 30/60). On a hit, they deal 1d6 slashing damage. <strong>If you are already proficient with playing cards as weapons, the damage die increases by one step (to 1d8).</strong></li>
                <li>Your ranged weapon attacks with playing cards ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.</li>
                <li>When you take the Attack action to throw a playing card, you can use a bonus action to throw another card.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Cards are 1d6 weapons (30/60). If already proficient, damage is 1d8. Attacks ignore 1/2 and 3/4 cover. Bonus action: Throw extra card.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Card Shark (Gaming Set)" supports="Gaming Set" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_DEADLY_PLAYING_CARD" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Cheat Death" type="Feat" source="Trick's Ledger of Many Tricks" id="ID_TRICK_FEAT_CHEAT_DEATH">
        <description>
            <p><em>"The grave can wait. I have one last hand to play."</em></p>
            <p>You have a standing arrangement with the powers that govern death—or perhaps you just know how to bluff the Reaper. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Constitution or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</li>
                <li>You have advantage on death saving throws.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>When reduced to 0 HP, drop to 1 HP instead. Advantage on Death Saves.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Cheat Death ASI" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>